Eistophos Science Club Collection 092
People's Archive, MLK Library
Eistophos Science Club Collection
1899-1997
People's Archive, MLK Library
Eistophos Science Club
092
0.5 Linear feet
1 Boxes
Biographical / Historical
The Eistophos Science Club was organized in 1870 as the Literary Reunion, and became the Washington Auxiliary of the National Science Club in 1893. The club was renamed the Eistophos Science Club in 1896. Their objective was to "unite for improvement and encouragement all women interested in the study of science and original research." The club held monthly meetings at which members read scientific papers and discussed current scientific issues.
Custodial History
This collection was relocated from DC Public Library's vertical files.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of the Eistophos Science Club's annual programs, constitution, by-laws, and correspondence, as well as items related to the history of the club.
Arrangement
Processed without series.
Societies and clubs; Science; Organizational Records; Correspondence
- Series 1
  - Programs, 1893-1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1944-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1971-1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - History (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Programs, 1987-1997 (Item 1)
    - "Sketch of the Eistophos", 1927 (Item 2)
    - History, 1927-1950 (Item 3)
    - History, 1893-1976 (Item 4)
  - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence regarding Eistophos Science Club materials in DCPL, 1948 (Item 1)
    - Correspondence regarding Eistophos Science Club materials in DCPL, 1963 (Item 2)
    - Correspondence regarding Eistophos Science Club materials in DCPL, 1978 (Item 3)